<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="mati@sz.home.pl">Mateusz Szczap</author>
    <title>FAQ</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>

	<section name="Frequently Asked Questions">
    
		<subsection name="What is JGGApi?">
		  <p>
		  The <b>JGGApi</b> is a Java Gadu-Gadu protocol implementation.
		  It is meant to be used for GUI application designers.
		  <b>JGGApi</b> uses that well-known design patterns that minimize learning curve.
		  As a result developers can write Gadu-Gadu clients faster than before.
		  </p>
		</subsection>

		<subsection name="What is the JGGApi license?">
		  <p>
			We use <b>GPL open source license</b>, therefore if you want to write the Gadu-Gadu client
			it must have <b>GPL license</b> as well.
			To find out more about open-source licenses point your browser at:
			<a href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/">www.opensource.org/licenses/</a>
		  </p>
		</subsection>
	
		<subsection name="Who develops JGGApi?">
			<p>
			The project was founded by <a href="mailto:mnaglik@gazeta.pl">Marcin Naglik (mnaglik@gazeta.pl)</a>
			in 2003.
			</p>
			<p>
			In November 2004 <a href="mailto:mati@sz.home.pl">Mateusz Szczap (mati@sz.home.pl)</a>
			joined the project and helped with the development and documentation process.
			</p>
		</subsection>

		<subsection name="What version of JVM (java virtual machine) can I use?">
			<p>
			The library requires JDK 1.4+.
			</p>
		</subsection>
		
		<subsection name="Who should use this library?">
			<p>
			This library can be used by anyone who wishes to write any kind of application
			or module that will interact with Gadu-Gadu server and it's users.
			</p>
			<p>
			Typical uses:
			<ul>
				<li>GUI application, ie. SWT/Swing.</li>
				<li>Proxy to bot such as A.L.I.C.E. (http://www.alicebot.org</li>
				<li>Http servlet gateway.</li>
				<li>Command line client, similar to ekg, using JCurses library.</li>
				<li>Flash client and gateway to java library.</li>
				<li>Gadu-Gadu WebService gateway.</li>
			</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
			It is also possible that this library could become part of CRM or workflow system
			implemented as a module that would allow interaction between some corporate system and
			IM users.
			</p>
		</subsection>
		
		<subsection name="Is it legal to use this library?">
			<p>
			This is quite unclear. Even though the company who developed Gadu-Gadu protocol states on their web-site
			that only applications authorized by that company can legally connect to servers supplied by SMS Express Sp. z.o.o
			company there is many open-source applications written mostly in C that use company's servers.
			Some applications such as: <b>EKG, Kadu, Gaim</b> are available in official Linux distributions.
			</p>
		</subsection>	

		<subsection name="Is JGGApi better then libgadu from EKG project?">
			<p>
			Yes and no. <b>Libgadu</b> from <b>EKG</b> project is more tested since it has a huge open-source
			community feedback. The disadvantage of the <b>libgadu</b> is that it is written in c language and
			there are some porting issues. <b>JGGApi</b> is a library written in Java
			and will run on every computer that has <b>JRE (Java Runtime Environment)</b> installed.
			</p>
			<p>
			In addition, the <b>JGGApi</b> is an object-oriented library and has a clear design. 
			It should be relatively easy for a new developer to write a Gadu-Gadu application
			using this library.
			</p>
		</subsection>

		<subsection name="I want to write a Gadu-Gadu midlet for my cell phone, can I use your library?">
			<p>
			No. Java enabled phones have J2ME VM. It is limited and JGGApi was
			developed using JDK 1.4.2 VM which is J2SE compilant library.
			</p>
		</subsection>

		<subsection name="How can I contribute to this project?">
			<p>
			If you are a Java developer who wants to write a Gadu-Gadu application you can
			help by submiting bug reports and patches fixing found issues.
			</p>
			<p>
			Also, there is a TODO list that always has some issues on it. Please feel free to look at
			it if you want to help us. If you convince us that you are valuable to the
			project and that you have Java skills we will be happy to include you on
			the list of our developers.
			</p>
			<p>
			You do not have to be a Java Developer or a Computer Engineer to contribute to this project. We are looking for
			web site mainteners and testers. Bug reports are very welcome.
			</p>
		</subsection>

		<subsection name="Does JGGApi depend on any library?">
			<p>
			Yes, it depends on commons-logging-1.0.4 framework and backport-util-concurrent from JDK 1.5.
			</p>
			<p>
			If you want to find out more about commons-logging framework take a look at:
			<a href="http://jakarta.apache.org/commons/logging/">http://jakarta.apache.org/commons/logging/</a>
			</p>
		</subsection>
	
		<subsection name="Where should I begin?">
			<p>
			First of all, you have to grab a fresh release of <b>JGGApi</b> from 
			<a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=79198">Download</a>.
			</p>
			<p>
			Second of all, please read our <a href="guide.html">Getting Started</a>.
			</p>
			<p>
			Third of all, your can browse JGGApi's <a href="apidocs/index.html">Java Docs</a> and
			<a href="xref/index.html">sources</a> online.
			</p>
			<p>
			Last but not least, start writing your application or module and get some hands on.
			</p>
		</subsection>
	</section>	
  </body>
</document>






