<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
	<properties>
		<title>JGGApi</title>
		<author>Marcin Naglik</author>
		<author>Mateusz Szczap</author>
	</properties>
	<body>
		<title></title>
		<section name="JGGApi - Gadu-Gadu protocol implementation.">
			<p> <b>JGGApi</b> is a Gadu-Gadu protocol implementation based on 
				specification from <b>EKG</b>. Gadu-Gadu is a very famous 
				Instant Messanger in Poland. </p>
			<p> Thanks to the libary it is very easy to create applications 
				that communicate with Gadu-Gadu server. It uses commonly used 
				design patterns (GoF) that minimizie the learnining curve for 
				developers. It has a good internal design and realizes a paradigm of 
				programming - <em>programming by extension</em>. 
				What is more, it will help developers that are 
				going to write applications similar to <b>Kadu</b>, <b>Gaim</b> 
				or command-line <b>EKG</b> to fasten their development process. 
				</p>
			<p> if you want to start using library and learn how to use it, 
				it is suggested that you take a look at our <a 
				href="guide.html">Getting Started</a> guide. </p>
		</section>
		<section name="News">
			<ul>
				<li>12-11-2005: Released <a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=79198">jggapi-1.6</a> version of <b>JGGApi</b>.</li>
				<li>04-01-2005: Written "session lifecycle" section in <a href="guide.html">Getting Started</a> Guide.</li>
				<li>03-01-2005: Released <a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=79198">jggapi-1.0-dev</a> version of <b>JGGApi</b>.</li>
				<li>03-01-2005: Written first part of <b>JGGApi</b> <a href="guide.html">Getting Started</a> Guide.</li>
			</ul>
		</section>
		<section name="Features">
			<p>
			<b>The JGGApi-1.6 allows:</b>
			 	<ul>
			 		<li>Send and receive messages.</li>
				 	<li>Retrieve confirmation of message delivery.</li>
				 	<li>Export and import of user's buddy list (contact list).</li>
				 	<li>Set own status which may include description and return date.</li>
				 	<li>Monitor statuses of users from buddy list.</li>
				 	<li>Add unwanted and nasty users to banned list.</li>
				 	<li>Read and write personal information to and from public directory.</li> 
					<li>Search public directory given user defined criteria.</li>
					<li>Register and unregister Gadu-Gadu account.</li>
					<li>Change account's password.</li>
					<li>Send forgotten password by e-mail.</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
		</section>
		<section name="Known Bugs and Limitations">
			<ul>
				<li>Write support for larger contact lists. Current 
					implementation is limited to contact lists that are not 
					more than 2048 bytes long.</li>
				<li>Add ability to send larger notify lists, i.e. list that is 
					send at the beginning to notify Gadu-Gadu server what users 
					we want to monitor.</li>
			</ul>
		</section>
		<section name="Planned Features">
			<ul>
				<li>Secured connections (SSL) support.</li>
				<li>Era Omnix discovery.</li>
				<li>Send and receive messages in Rich Text Format.</li>
				<li>Send and receive files and images.</li>
				<li>DCC connections: send and receive messages in RTF, files and images.</li>
			</ul>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>